

716.308.5463



Luke.c.darling@gmail.com



Lewiston. NY



Linkedin.com/in/ lukecdarling

FXPFRTISE

Azure (AZ-900 Certification)
SAFe (Scaled Agile)
Leadership
Solution Architecture
DevOps
Programming
Automation
Continuous Learning

EDUCATION

Change Management

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE
Electrical Engineering
Cum laude
State University of NY at Buffalo
2010 – 2013

BACHELOR OF ARTS
Mathematics – Concentration in
Computing and Applied
Mathematics
Cum laude
State University of NY at Buffalo
2003-2008

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Resourceful, independent self-starter and customer-focused Innovator with an extensive background in Azure Cloud development and architecture, analyzing processes, engineering automated solutions, creating and performing quality tests, and designing software. Experienced in analyzing business problems and developing solutions using a variety of technical skills and tools within an Agile framework. Skilled in developing business plans, requirement specifications, user documentation, and architectural diagrams.

EXPERIENCE

IT SECTION HEAD - Data Services

Moog, Buffalo, New York / July 2021 - Current

- Designing Data Solutions for ML and Reporting utilizing Azure Synapse Analytics and Spark
- Rebuilding the existing Data Warehouse architecture and updating the future path to utilize Lakehouse Architecture with a Data Lake (ADLS2) and Delta Lake (within Synapse)
- Aligning various organizational teams (HR, Finance, Operating Groups) on best data practices including the creation of Data Cubes for both Operational and Analytical Reporting

IT SECTION HEAD – Application Enablement and DevOps

Moog, Buffalo, New York / June 2020 – July 2021

- Building a team that can drive the best patterns and practices for Development Teams to follow
- Leading the way in determining the software, practices, and applications of DevOps within the Organization
- Provide Automation, Cloud Consultation, Hands-On Work, Monitoring and Alerting, and R&D as a service to the Organization

IT SECTION HEAD - Tech Solutions

Moog, Buffalo, New York / March 2020 - June 2020

- Manage a Technical team (domestic and offshore)
- Lead the team in developing/implementing solutions to technical blockers with applications
- Provide the team with the technologies and tools necessary to perform their development tasks
- Developing and designing application roadmaps

TECH LEAD/DEVOPS ENGINEER

Moog, Buffalo, New York / Jan 2019 – March 2020

- Remove technical blockers and develop/implement solutions to fix existing issues with legacy applications that have been migrated to the cloud and develop new applications
- Continuously Improve/Develop DevOps pipelines and tools (Azure DevOps, ARM Templates, Terraform, PowerShell Scripts) to assist with development and deployment of features and updates to existing applications
- Assigned to high-level projects by the CIO/Senior Leadership that have high visibility and are critical for the future success of the organization (SAP Implementation, Supply Chain)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C#
Java J2EE
C++
Delphi
.NET Core
Python

SCRIPTING

Powershell Batch Files AutoIT AutoHotKey

DATABASES

Microsoft SQL MSSQL Azure SQL Cosmos DB

TOOLS

Visual Studio 2019
VS Code
MS SQL Management
Studio
Git
VSTS
Azure Data Studio
Netbeans
Rad Studio
Matlab
Team Foundation Server

SOFTWARE

ServiceNow
Microsoft Visio
Microsoft Dynamics
OpconXPS
ACHplus
MS Office Suite
Serv-U
Various ETL Design and
Data Mapping Tools
Notepad++

EXPERIENCE continued

DEVOPS ENGINEER

Systems Personnel (Contractor at Moog), Buffalo, New York / July 2018 – Jan 2019

- Engineer build and release pipelines in Azure DevOps (Formerly VSTS)
- Build Azure Infrastructure for .NET (C#) and Java Apps including PaaS WebApps (utilizing App Services)
- Develop optimal solutions with various cloud services including Logic Apps, PaaS containers, and Azure Automation

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Liazon, Buffalo, New York / October 2017 – July 2018

- Help improve the quality of software by writing automated tests and performing code reviews.
- Work and communicate effectively in an agile team environment.
- Develop, maintain and support the Business Objects environment.
- Design and test fact tables and dimensions within the organization's Data Warehouse Environment.
- Design and support the ETL environment by building SSIS packages and workflows.
- Build and maintain the queries, stored procedures, and views necessary to support reporting, the Data Warehouse, and the various needs of Business Units.
- Analyze end-to-end processes for performance and then utilize various tool to tune performance.
- Utilize GIT for effective source control and management.

ETL ANALYST

Liazon, Buffalo, New York / 2015 – 2017 (2 years)

- Development, testing, and production maintenance of payroll files. Core responsibilities include B2B client interaction, requirements gathering, and design of payroll files to specifications. Responsibilities also include interfacing with offshore teams and utilizing data mapping tools.
- Designed custom system to audit data. To date this has prevented twenty customers from receiving incorrect data and is entirely automated.
- Write initial reviews, functional designs, technical requirements and documentation, test strategies, statements of work, and production implementations.
- Administrate Team Foundation Server for the ETL team to provide source code management for ETL custom-built code.
- Design efficient and repeatable processes for payroll to reduce time-to-build and to allow automation of future builds.
- Troubleshoot and determine flaws in current process and build solutions to fix the flaws.
- Collaborate with project managers, HR directors, payroll vendors, and other team members across the organization to complete payroll projects.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

UDEMY Training Microsoft Learn Azure Fundamentals Certified

Professional Reading List

Completed

The Pragmatic Programmer The Clean Coder 97 Things Every Programmer Should Know Essential Pascal Head First SQL SQL Server 2012 T-SQL Recipes Head First Java The Passionate Programmer Head First C# Head First Software Development Head First Design Patterns Dynamic SQL The Art of Agile Development Ship It Struts 2 in Action Microsoft Azure Enterprise

In-Progress

Application Development

Fundamental Algorithms
Big Java
Building Microservices
Applications on Microsoft
Azure Designing,
Developing, Deploying, and
Monitoring

EXPERIENCE continued

SENIOR SYSTEM ANALYST

First Niagara Bank, Lockport, New York / 2010 – 2015 (3 years)

- Participate in flagship initiatives, which involve the implementation of vendor software and/or home-grown applications aligned with First Niagara's strategic plan. Core responsibilities include coordinating development support from multiple IT Operations and Vendor support teams to build stable platforms which institute and/or replace First Niagara's Legacy Systems.
- Member of the critical implementation team accountable for the integration and deployment of First Niagara's BAI Processing Software.
 Core responsibilities include system design, development, configuration, testing, training, and go-live phases.
- Develop custom Delphi (Object-Oriented Pascal) programs to support Jack Henry's Synergy and Unisys' MCP Systems.
- Develop and test SQL queries to extract information for several key applications.

SUPPORT ENGINEER

First Niagara Bank, Lockport, New York / 2010 – 2015 (1 year)

- Maintained support and user documentation for several applications including workflow, UML diagrams, Visio diagrams, and runbooks.
- Experienced in supporting software applications including data protection, product setup and testing, software release installation and release testing.

COMPUTER OPERATOR SPECIALIST

First Niagara Bank, Lockport, New York / 2010 – 2015 (1 year)

COMPUTER OPERATOR I

M&T Bank, Amherst, New York / 2005 – 2010 (2 years)

OUTPUT DISTRIBUTION OPERATOR

M&T Bank, Amherst, New York / 2005 – 2010 (3 years)

REFERENCES



Rod Smith

Former Co-Worker, First Vice President, Valley Bank N.J. 716.341.1014, rws@warilysoftware.com



Nick Pulvino

Former Co-Worker, Business Intelligence Manager, ACV 716.812.7863, Nick.pulvino@gmail.com



Sadie Hambalek

Former-Worker, Implementation Project Manager, Liazon 716.954.8118, <u>Sadie.hambalek@liazon.com</u>

Azure Technical Stack

2018 - 2019

- Resource Groups
- App Services
- Azure SQL (PaaS)
- Hybrid Connection Manager
- Power Apps
- Logic Apps
- Key Vaults
- Application Insights

2019 - 2021

- Azure SQL (Elastic Pools)
- Storage Accounts
- Azure Monitor
- Azure Automation
- Service Principals
- AAD (Azure Active Directory)
- Virtual Machines/ Managed SQL Instances
- Azure Site Recovery
- Recovery Services vaults
- VNet
- Function Apps

2021 - 2022

- Azure Synapse Analytics
- Azure Data Factory
- Stream Analytics
- IoT Hub
- Event Hubs
- Azure Databricks
- PowerBl
- ADLG2
- QnA makers
- Machine Learning
- TSI (Time Series Insights)